PROFILE

Precociously oriented towards mechanics, bodywork and car painting, I spent 7 years in a semi-professional environment that didn't satisfy my ambition and my taste for reflection. As a result, I reoriented myself in an environment that fulfilled me. As a fan of online pc games, the reflexion and logic that I found in these games fitted in perfectly with what a programmer's job requires, and I immediately liked it as i started my studies.

At 26 years old, I've become the proud father of a little girl born in October 2023, who makes me want to push myself even harder.

SKILLS

LANGUAGE



























IND ME & PORTFOLIO







LANGUAGES

- French (native)
- Fluent and professional English
- Learning German

INTERESTS

- · Arts and popular science, interest in Al development, LLM, neural network systems, machine learning, deep learning, VR, procedural generation.
- Video games and their development (CIG, Riot Games, IMC, Gaijin, Grinding Gear Games)
- Travels: Spain, Iceland, England, Tunisia, Greece, Belgium, Italy, Germany, Florida

CONTACT ME

thomas.boulanger.auditeur@lecnam.net

THOMAS BOULANGER

STUDENT VIDEO GAMES PROGRAMMING

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE & PROJECTS

Second year's Master project | oct 2023 - feb 2024

Development of the game Shokh, a third-person parkour fast-paced game.

I was one of the three dev on this project of ten students. I was able to code aspects of game logic such as a checkpoint system, a dynamic camera in relation to the player's speed as well as **heatmap** and **data collection** and analysis systems for playtesting.

Writing of a master's thesis | jul 2023 - sep 2023

Writing of Optimization Techniques for Enhanced Performance in Unity thesis where I explored several ways to optimize fps and overall performance of Unity project.

First year's Master project | mar 2022 - jun 2023

Development of the game **AAAaaaAh**, a coop couch game from 2 to 4 players.

I was the only developer on this 4 months project, I had to code all the architecture as well as all the logic of the game and the systems.

The game was using a character controller halfway between Physics and Animator that make it very juicy to play and handle.

Exkee, Video Games Development Studio | Jul 2020 - aug 2020

Creation of the **Exkee.com** website using WordPress.

Creation of the mobile video game Poker Run.

Carrosserie Du Garlaban | oct 2017 - jul 2019

Bodywork and painting on all car models.

First prize at the 45th Olympiades des Métiers, "Sheet metal and bodywork" category.

Carrosserie LE MILANO | sep 2016 - jul 2017

Bodywork and mechanical work on classic, sports and luxury cars.

Delivery of vehicles to customers and responsible for administrative formalities.

RENAULT CATALAN | sep 2012 - aug 2016

Mechanical work on all type of vehicules.

EDUCATION

Master's degree in Video Games & Interactive Media, Programmation specialization at Cnam Enjmin Angoulême | 2022 - 2024

Concepts covered: OpenGL | Pixel/Fragment Shader | Engine Programmation | Wave Function Collapse (WFC) | Procedural Generation | Arduino Programmaming | World generation.

3 year diploma in video game programming & game design at Esa Games Carpentras | 2019 - 2022

Concepts covered: Dijkstra | A* | Procedural generation | Save | Command Pattern | Events | Network | Binary Space Partitioning | Finite State Machine (FSM) | Behavior Tree | MinMaxing.

CQP Car Bodywork & Car Painter | 2017 - 2019

NVQ Car Bodywork | 2016 - 2017

BTEC Motor vehicle maintenance (with honours) | 2014 - 2016

NVQ Motor vehicle maintenance | 2012 - 2014